Katherine Kim

Technical Writer

Organized and accomplished technical writer with 2 years of experience writing and editing user-faced technical documents, including user guides, release notes, and man pages. Quick learner with authoring programs and content management systems. Social collaborator working with subject matter experts to gather technical information to write concise and user-friendly documentation.

kimhkat@gmail.com 🔀

408-431-3735

San Jose, United States ♀

linkedin.com/in/kimhkat in

kimhkat.github.io 🎧

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer IISynopsys

12/2020 - Present

Mountain View, CA

- Support documentation for 7 products, including user guides, release notes, and customer training slides.
- Drive core team meetings to advocate for accurate technical content in documentation.
- Update product documentation through internal release management system.
- Edit man pages for grammar and technical issues, such as missing or inaccurate information.

Technical Writer I Synopsys

05/2019 - 12/2020

Mountain View, CA

- Support documentation for 4 products, including user guides, release notes, customer training slides.
- Document new features through release notes and user guide updates for every service pack and major release.
- Coordinate with subject matter experts (SMEs) to ensure accurate technical features and usage examples for end users.
- Peer review and edit user guides and release notes for every release.

EDUCATION

B.A. Professional, Technical, Business, and Scientific Writing

San José State University

2017 - 2019

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Joined Man Page Editing Initiative (03/2021 - Present)

Volunteered to take on additional responsibilities to review man pages. Edit syntax for technical clarity and grammar, while adhering to the publication style guide.

Published eLearning Module (07/2020 - 09/2020)

Created an eLearning module published for customers to learn about the supported product. Compiled marketing information and SME input to produce an introduction course. Used Articulate Storyline to design the UX and audio input.

Participated in DITA Testing (09/2019 - 09/2019)

Learned DITA in oXygen XML Editor in 3 weeks. Converted 7 user guides from Adobe FrameMaker to oXygen XML Editor by hard deadline.

INTERESTS

Indoor gardening

True crime podcasts

Slime ASMR

Learning Spanish